<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science | Solveig Bjørholt</title>
    <link>//localhost:4321/tags/data-science/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:4321/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:4321/media/icon_hu9275620438765660929.png</url>
      <title>Data Science</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/tags/data-science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Data Science Hackathon</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/teaching/isssv1337/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/teaching/isssv1337/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I established the course Politicial Data Science Hackathon together with Alex Moltzau in 2022. The course was held six weeks over summer at the International Summer School in 2022 and 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this course, we collaborated with organizations from work life. They provided a problem statement based on a real-life challenge in their organization, and the students learned data science techniques to work on the problem over the summer. In the end, they wrote a report and held a presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course attracted students from various disciplines, allowing students to work in cross-disciplinary teams. This led us to also teach some fundamentals about how to work together in diverse teams to learn from and utilize each others&amp;rsquo; strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substantially, students learn fundamental data science techniques such as fundamental R programming with tidyverse, data wrangling, descriptive statistics, data collection, visualization, text analysis, and supervised and unsupervised machine learning. Importantly, they learn why these techniques are useful by applying them to a case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been course convener and lecturer in both 2022 and 2023, lecturing together with Eric Nilsen, Jonas W. Schmid, Sondre Elstad and Louisa Boulaziz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://shiny.uio.no/political_data_science_hackathon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;course book&lt;/a&gt; for 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; name=&#34;iframe&#34; src=&#34;https://shiny.uio.no/political_data_science_hackathon&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
