<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching | Solveig Bjørholt</title>
    <link>//localhost:4321/teaching/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:4321/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Teaching</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:4321/media/icon_hu9275620438765660929.png</url>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/teaching/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Statistics and Methods</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/teaching/stv1020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/teaching/stv1020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have held multiple lectures in introductory courses for bachelor students into statistics and quantitative methods. I have held these courses at the University of Oslo, Oslo New University College and the University of South-Eastern Norway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These courses rely on the book &lt;em&gt;Fundamentals of Political Science Research&lt;/em&gt; by Paul M. Kellstedt and Guy D. Whitten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contents of the course are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to social science methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Causal inference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data collection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Descriptive statistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bivariate analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical inference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regression assumptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Data Science Hackathon</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/teaching/isssv1337/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/teaching/isssv1337/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I established the course Politicial Data Science Hackathon together with Alex Moltzau in 2022. The course was held six weeks over summer at the International Summer School in 2022 and 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this course, we collaborated with organizations from work life. They provided a problem statement based on a real-life challenge in their organization, and the students learned data science techniques to work on the problem over the summer. In the end, they wrote a report and held a presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course attracted students from various disciplines, allowing students to work in cross-disciplinary teams. This led us to also teach some fundamentals about how to work together in diverse teams to learn from and utilize each others&amp;rsquo; strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substantially, students learn fundamental data science techniques such as fundamental R programming with tidyverse, data wrangling, descriptive statistics, data collection, visualization, text analysis, and supervised and unsupervised machine learning. Importantly, they learn why these techniques are useful by applying them to a case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been course convener and lecturer in both 2022 and 2023, lecturing together with Eric Nilsen, Jonas W. Schmid, Sondre Elstad and Louisa Boulaziz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://shiny.uio.no/political_data_science_hackathon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;course book&lt;/a&gt; for 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; name=&#34;iframe&#34; src=&#34;https://shiny.uio.no/political_data_science_hackathon&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Text Data</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/teaching/stv2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/teaching/stv2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I shared course convening responsibilities and held half the lectures of the Big Text Data course with Martin Søyland in Autumn 2022. The course is taught in Norwegian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course teaches fundamentals within quantitative text analysis and language models, from gathering text data, parsing and preprocessing to models such as sentiment analysis, topic models and supervised learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://shiny.uio.no/content/1cd1d031-ddef-4e6d-855e-87e3bedc5fd8/notatbok.html#introduksjon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;course book&lt;/a&gt; for 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; name=&#34;iframe&#34; src=&#34;https://shiny.uio.no/content/1cd1d031-ddef-4e6d-855e-87e3bedc5fd8/notatbok.html#introduksjon&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideathon</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/teaching/ideathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/teaching/ideathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2022, I arranged an Ideathon for the Norwegian ministries together with Alex Moltzau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this Ideathon, we let course participants work in teams to find solutions to exisitng challenges within the ministries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We collected challenges from employees and made problem statements out of them. Putting the Ideathon participants in teams, we taught techniques for idea generation and agile group work. Then, we supervised the teams as they worked on finding novel solutions the given challenges.
Two externals were invited in to hold inspiring talks about how they solved challenges in the public sector. On the final day, each team presented their solution to the others, and the participants voted forth one winner team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slides are in Norwegian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;Day1.pdf&#34;&gt;Slides for Day 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;Day2.pdf&#34;&gt;Slides for Day 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
