<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching | Solveig Bjørholt</title>
    <link>//localhost:4321/teaching/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:4321/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Teaching</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:4321/media/icon_hu9275620438765660929.png</url>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/teaching/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Statistics and Methods</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/teaching/stv1020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/teaching/stv1020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have delivered multiple lectures in introductory statistics and quantitative methods courses for bachelor students. These courses were taught at the University of Oslo, Oslo New University College, and the University of South-Eastern Norway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The courses are based on the book &lt;em&gt;Fundamentals of Political Science Research&lt;/em&gt; by Paul M. Kellstedt and Guy D. Whitten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Course topics include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to social science methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Causal inference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data collection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Descriptive statistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bivariate analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical inference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regression assumptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Data Science Hackathon</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/teaching/isssv1337/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/teaching/isssv1337/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This course integrates team-based problem-solving with real-world work-life cases provided by stakeholders from industry and public sector. Participants also gain hands-on experience with data science methods.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Moltzau and I established this course in 2022, which has been held over six weeks during the International Summer School in both 2022 and 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this course, we collaborated with various organizations that provided real-life challenges for our students to address. Students learned data science techniques to tackle these problems, ultimately writing reports and presenting their findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course attracted students from diverse disciplines, fostering cross-disciplinary teamwork. To maximize the benefits of this diversity, we also taught foundational skills for effective collaboration in varied teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students gained practical experience in fundamental data science techniques, including R programming with tidyverse, data wrangling, descriptive statistics, data collection, visualization, text analysis, and supervised and unsupervised machine learning. They applied these techniques to real-world cases, enabling them to understand the utility of these techniques in practical scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the course convener and lecturer, I have taught both years alongside Eric Nilsen, Jonas W. Schmid, Sondre Elstad, and Louisa Boulaziz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://shiny.uio.no/political_data_science_hackathon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;course book&lt;/a&gt; for 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; name=&#34;iframe&#34; src=&#34;https://shiny.uio.no/political_data_science_hackathon&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Text Data</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/teaching/stv2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/teaching/stv2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Autumn 2022, I co-convened and co-lectured the Big Text Data course with Martin Søyland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course covers the fundamentals of quantitative text analysis and language models. Topics include gathering, parsing, and preprocessing text data, as well as advanced techniques like sentiment analysis, topic modeling, and supervised learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://shiny.uio.no/content/1cd1d031-ddef-4e6d-855e-87e3bedc5fd8/notatbok.html#introduksjon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;course book&lt;/a&gt; for 2022. Please note that the course material is in Norwegian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; name=&#34;iframe&#34; src=&#34;https://shiny.uio.no/content/1cd1d031-ddef-4e6d-855e-87e3bedc5fd8/notatbok.html#introduksjon&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideathon</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/teaching/ideathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/teaching/ideathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2022, together with Alex Moltzau, I organized an Ideathon for the Norwegian ministries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this event, course participants were grouped into teams to address existing challenges within the ministries. We gathered these challenges directly from employees, formulating them into problem statements for the participants to tackle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We taught techniques for idea generation and agile group work, then supervised the teams as they developed innovative solutions. The Ideathon featured two external speakers who shared their experiences of overcoming challenges in the public sector, providing inspiration to the participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the final day, each team presented their solutions, and the participants voted to select the winning team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Please note: The slides are in Norwegian.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;Day1.pdf&#34;&gt;Slides for Day 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;Day2.pdf&#34;&gt;Slides for Day 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
